She's worth all the trouble.
My Week with Marilyn is a drama, romance film directed by Simon Curtis.
London, 1956.
Genius actor and film director Laurence Olivier is about to begin the shooting of his upcoming
movie, premiered in 1957 as The Prince and the Showgirl, starring Marilyn Monroe.
Young Colin Clark, who dreams on having a career in movie business,
manages to get a job on the set as third assistant director.
Marilyn Monroe, played by Michelle Williams.
Sir Laurence Olivier, played by Kenneth Branagh.
Colin Clark, played by Eddie Redmayne.
Milton Greene, played by Dominic Cooper.
Roger Smith, played by Philip Jackson.
Sir Owen Morshead, played by Derek Jacobi.
My Week with Marilyn is a 2011 biographical film drama directed
by Simon Curtis and written by Adrian Hodges.
It stars Michelle Williams, Kenneth Branagh, Eddie Redmayne, Dominic
Cooper, Julia Ormond, Emma Watson, and Judi Dench.
Based on two books by Colin Clark, it depicts the making of the 1957 film The Prince and the
Showgirl, which starred Marilyn Monroe (Williams) and Laurence Olivier (Branagh).
The film concerns the week during the shooting of the film when Monroe was escorted around London by Clark
(Redmayne), after her husband Arthur Miller (Dougray Scott) had returned to the United States.
Principal photography began on 4 October 2010, at Pinewood Studios.
Filming took place at Saltwood Castle, White Waltham
Airfield, and on locations in and around London.
Curtis also used the same studio in which Monroe had
shot The Prince and the Showgirl in 1956.
My Week with Marilyn had its world premiere at the New York Film Festival on 9 October
2011, and was shown at the Mill Valley Film Festival two days later.
The film was released on 23 November 2011, in the United
States, and on 25 November in the United Kingdom.
The film received generally positive reviews and grossed $35 million worldwide.
Williams and Branagh were nominated for the Academy Awards for
Best Actress and Best Supporting Actor respectively.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship, countryside,
based on novel or book, cinema on cinema, movie business.
The tone is emotional.